Guide to the Ivo John Lederer Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Ivo John Lederer papers
1919-1968
1952-1958
MS 1751
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
The papers include background material and notes collected by Ivo J. Lederer as a scholar and author of works on Yugoslavia and Russia.
Lederer, Ivo J.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Slavic Collection,1996.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Ivo John Lederer was born on December 11, 1929, in Zagreb, Croatia. After the Nazis invaded the city, Lederer's family fled to Italy and eventually received permission to settle in the United States. In 1951, Lederer received a B.A. from the University of Colorado and in 1957 he completed a doctorate at Princeton. In a twenty-three year teaching career, he held faculty positions in contemporary Russian and Eastern European history at Princeton, Yale, and Stanford and published on Yugoslavia at the Paris Peace Conference after World War I. In 1977, he began a second career organizing discussions between government and business leaders on the interaction of foreign and business policies. Lederer died on June 18, 1998.
Scope and Contents
The papers include background material and notes collected by Ivo J. Lederer as a scholar and author of works on Yugoslavia and Russia.
World War, 1914-1918 -- Peace; Russia -- Study and teaching; Yugoslavia; Lederer, Ivo J.
- Inventory
  - Russia [background material, notes], 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Russia and Europe" [typescripts of translation of work by Danilevskii], undated (Box 1, Folder 2 - 9)
  - Seton-Watson, R. W., 1952, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Yugoslavia
    - Background material, notes, some correspondence from Bogumil Vosnjak, 1952-1958 (Box 1, Folder 11 - 12)
    - Statistical data, undated (Box 2, Folder 13 - 15)
  - Yugoslavia and the Paris Peace Conference
    - Background material, 1919-1956, undated (Box 2, Folder 16 - 20)
    - Interview notes, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Notebook, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)